i thought about wearing my halloween
costume i have the scariest halloween
costume
i go is winnie the pooh
think about it
what's creepier than me showing up to
your front door wearing only a red half
shirt
carrying a pot of honey
singing some white zombie
[Music]
pretty creepy i would know i've seen me
naked
i love it i love halloween i do i like
going to a haunted house y'all ever go
to a haunted house
there's about 12 of you the rest of you
already live in a haunted house is that
what's going on here
i'm gonna leave my haunted house to go
to another one i got my own problems at
home
i love it man i love going to a haunted
house i do i like watching all the shows
on tv about haunted houses and they got
a bunch of those too you know like
american horror story and all those
ghost hunting shows and scooby doo it's
awesome
the thing is it's always something huge
that's haunted it's always like a
haunted mansion or a haunted prison or a
haunted sam's club or something like
that it's like something really big
and they never show a haunted trailer
and i don't know about you
but i refuse to believe that nobody has
ever been killed in a trailer and now i
wanted to come back and haunt that thing
you know there are haunted trailers out
there somewhere and the people who live
in them are just too lazy to report it
you know
you know there's some dude he's just
sitting in his trailer and all of a
sudden he hears boo
[Music]
what in the world was that go get me a
beer i'm gonna get my gun that's what
i'm gonna do
turn the tv on swamp people is on
i can't find the remote control you know
that
most ghosts are wearing like a civil war
outfit or a flowing gown or their ihop
uniform and
this ghost is wearing a white tank top
and camo pants and the same as earl
it's a scary ghost right there
most kids most kids their favorite
holiday is christmas not when you're
from a large family because it might not
be your turn to get a present that year
a large family your favorite holiday is
halloween because it is incentive based
if you hustle you can stock up for the
year
halloween comes around all you know is
you're going to run for as hard as you
can as long as you can a lot of kids try
to tell you oh halloween ends at 10 p.m
wrong halloween ends when people quit
answering the door
and most kids they're just concerned
about what they're going to be for
halloween you ask a kid from a large
family what are you going to be i'm
going to be as fast as i can
you're going to wear a costume a costume
would slow me down
and you hate it when you get to that
nice lady's house that nice lady that
just wants to talk halloween night and
she wants to have a conversation and
what are you supposed to be i do not
have time for this
put the candy in the bag
i had one brother he wouldn't even talk
to people halloween night they tried to
talk to me just look at him and go did
it
i've seen grown men just back away just
throw candy at him maybe he'll leave
[Laughter]
we had a new guy move into the
neighborhood one year he just looked at
my brother and said a scoozy
and you know what you hate you you well
actually what you love is the lazy guy's
house the lazy guy
halloween night the lazy the guy that
puts a bowl full of candy
on his front porch
with the note
please take one
we not only dump the bowl we took the
bowl
we took the note because you want to
show other kids you got to read this
this is funny
and we use pillowcases because you know
though i mean that pillowcases you can't
fill them up but it doesn't it's
physically impossible we try it every
year but you got the pillowcase and then
you see that kid with the paper bag
whack
oh i'd love to help you pick up your
candy
[Laughter]
see because it's all in how you look at
things folks you just gotta think
positive you gotta think outside the box
for example i celebrate halloween in
august because when you show up at
someone's house at night wearing a mask
in august you get better stuff
[Applause]
before this i was a teacher i got a
i taught high school english state of
missouri for a couple years and teachers
in here tonight by chance you know are
you are you really
jet i really can't see you just yelled
out what do you teach
art
art okay that's kind of different you
tell your students in art there's no
such thing as a stupid question
that's such a lie isn't it
because let me tell you something when
you teach not only are there stupid
questions those are generally the only
kind you get
[Music]
it's the middle of october my kids were
studying legends sleepy hollow headless
horseman that whole thing i've got kid
in the back of the room raising his hand
said mr thornsberry wouldn't that be
really weird if halloween and friday the
13th happened on the same day
that'd be spooky
who can tell me what the most uh popular
item is at second-hand stores anyone
that is faced on a season that's the
clue that i will give you
christmas sweaters would be number two
halloween costume very good does that
come from you sir have you ever done
that bought halloween costume at the
goodwill no but you've seen it happen
right
and by saying it it's make your costume
out of the things they have not buy an
old halloween costume because no one
would do that they're not made well
enough to get a second spin plus they
make them so well who would buy an old
halloween really remember the ones that
we had to wear the one-dimensional
plastic face mask that fasted with a
rubber band that would snap off your
face after the second house because the
metal piece would flip sideways and
shoot through the hole and you can't get
it back so you're trying to stretch it
under the staple and get it through the
hole but that doesn't work because
there's a tear where the hole is so
you're like holding up the mask with one
hand and dragging a candy with the other
you're knocking on doors with your rear
end yeah this is working out perfectly
i've got a box of milk duds i'm ready to
pass out this is not an exciting day
i'm gonna go home and get my ghost
costume
remember the ghost costume that was our
insurance policy right
fallback option if all else failed you
could always be a ghost he's right there
on the bed waiting for you that's how
easy that is
pull up that sheet you drop it over your
head you're a ghost
but we spot the bed wetter's a lot
quicker on halloween too couldn't you
thank god we look at that
a specter with a bladder control problem
i'm doubly frightened
but hopefully you never have to use the
fallback option because whatever your
kids want to be for halloween that's the
costume you get them when i was a kid i
was batman every year because i was such
a huge fan of of batman and kids now
that's more popular even when i was a
kid but it's so different now because
kids dress up like batman they've got
body armor on and remember our batman
like from all adam west was our batman
right that's how i thought batman was
supposed to behave i was knocking on
doors i wasn't just batman i was adam
west as batman right
trick
or
treat good citizen
carefully
produce
your sugar
coated confections
and place them in the
candy suburban utility building
sure it took me a little longer to trick
or treat but i was i was method
anybody ever go too late the costume
that your son or daughter asked you for
it wasn't there anymore then you got to
literally scrape whatever's at the
bottom of the barrel the whole ride home
you're like okay how do i sell this as
the intended costume how am i gonna
convince an eight-year-old boy that
holly hobby is an appropriate look
you're like
no it looks fantastic just uh
stick close to your brother's strawberry
shortcake everything's gonna be fine
because halloween is about disguise
and then you have to give your kids the
rules of halloween remember those rules
of halloween number one was the apple
rule was that somebody gave you an apple
you had to consider the possibility of
what
exactly right that some nut may have put
a razor blade in the apple it is then
your responsibility and i mean this
to whip that apple off the side of that
guy's house as hard as you possibly can
it's one of the unwritten laws of
halloween like the one that says if you
put a pumpkin out in front of your house
may as well put with it a sign that says
hey would you guys please kick this all
over the neighborhood please we were we
were hoping you'd have a punting contest
with it out front and then smear the
what's left of the jack-o-lantern all
over our siding we'd like that
those are the same people but all their
candy one big bowl right
leave it on the front step what does air
sign say anyone
take one
where do you live take one are you
serious
i'm the first get to that house i'm
taking the bowl too
i've got a decorative mother's day gift
as far as i'm concerned
take one you're an idiot take one
how about the guy that forgot halloween
remember that guy didn't have any idea
what day it was no candy you get there
now he has to find things in the house
to give you yeah that always worked out
well didn't it
slim gems and robitussin no that's
perfect
i have bronchitis
here kid here's an egg
scoop of peanut butter for you my friend
it's like man if the guy next door has
bread what a day this would be
but a boy can dream
my niece and nephew is love i still go
trick-or-treating with him i dress up in
everything i was michael jackson last
year
i was i didn't even have to put on a
costume i just did my nose like this
[Applause]
if you didn't laugh at that i hope you
fall down a small flight of stairs
almost passed out for you people
i have a little nephew evan yvonne i
don't know what the heck his name is
i got him a halloween mask you know the
cool mask for the kids today the rubber
ones your pump of blood comes out of the
pool i don't like it uncle you little
brat
do you know what i had what you had
growing up see if you relate to this i'm
surprised i'm still alive
i had a plastic suffocation chamber with
a thin rubber band that ripped your hair
out of the roots
the eye slits were on the forehead you
can't see
the only hole in the mask was that
little slit in the mouth
but you didn't breathe whether you just
stuck your tongue out
one year it got stuck
like a flirty chewbacca the whole night
sorry
i named after my dad but here's the deal
i'm a comedian so i'm supposed to be
funny my dad's one of those guys that
thinks he's funny you know those guys
that was my dad you just love to tell
jokes and play games with his kids this
is one of my dad's favorite games to
play with us growing up hey
see if you can find your way home from
here
[Laughter]
halloween dressed me up as a speed bump
i got home my candy was smashed
you know it wasn't smashed candy corn
that's the worst candy you could get for
halloween candy corn you might as well
hand out chalk
you ever eat chalk
you look like a look like a dog eating a
pickle
wow
oh man i'm just glad i don't have to
hand out halloween candy anymore now
that my sister has kids that go over
there
because when i first stood in i had to
hand it out
i didn't have all of it ready because
there were like 4 000 kids
so i went to my trick-or-treating at my
neighbors
she's like what are you supposed to be
i'm like prepared give me the candy
let's not belabor this
beautiful time springtime beautiful time
i love summer
i love the holiday season too it's like
i can't wait for the next holiday season
all the time
my favorite holiday
christmas
i love me some christmas
my least favorite holiday
is every man in this room's least
favorite holiday ladies valentine's day
every man in here hates valentine's day
ladies and here's why
for guys valentine's day is exactly the
same holiday as halloween
think about it young lady it's a day
where he got to dress up
pretend he's somebody he ain't
and then he gives away candy
before that i worked on the queen mary a
ship in long beach california they have
a halloween haunted maze thingy they do
every year i was a vampire on that thing
that was tough for me i don't know
anything about vampires there's only two
types of vampires that i know there's a
modern day vampire that's like p90x
glitter
[Music]
and then there's count chocula
just a lovable cereal character
both of those aren't scary i had to be
scary not to mention the least
intimidating dude ever i'd pop out and
seven-year-old kids would be like i
could take him
i just had to settle for being creepy i
just grabbed my cape draped it over and
whispered in people's ears hey i'm naked
into this
got the biggest screams
the place i was at was supposed to be
actually
haunted i didn't see anything i was
creeped out though the whole time i
watch all those ghost shows on tv you
guys watch those at all
there's one the other day i saw i was on
the animal planet and people claim that
their pets see ghosts
this lady was like my dog rocky just
started barking at the wall for no
reason
i was like yeah it's called being a dog
[Music]
my great aunt once had a full
conversation with a coffee mug it
doesn't mean her cup is haunted
it just means her pills stopped working
and that dog doesn't know he saw a ghost
right at the end of the day that dog
goes up to his other dog friend is like
hey i just saw a blurry guy and then the
other dog's like that's not that weird
my tail's trying to murder me
we have weird theories about ghosts
we think the cemetery is haunted i was
asking my buddy about it he's like dudes
from all the people who died at the
cemetery i'm like nobody died at the
cemetery
that's the shadiest death of all time
i'm still alive not for long
it's always the same ghosts it's always
a little girl in the white dress
like there are no caveman ghosts
anywhere
maybe there are caveman ghosts maybe
they're the ones who turn lights on and
off just like ah
[Music]
we gotta update our ghosts right someday
people are gonna be seeing ghosts of us
our generation someday you're just gonna
get a text message like boo
just a twitter update like i'm right
behind you
hashtag i'm a ghost
it's probably already happening on
myspace but nobody knows because no one
goes on there anymore
tom's the only one like what was that
that joke was for four of you in here
but i like it so i do it
my favorite time of the year to be a cop
is halloween time
because you see the craziest stuff
and uh
you know it it comes at you you got to
deal with it this last halloween i'm
driving down the boulevard and there's a
lady on the corner dressed up like a
white cotton ball
so i was like what rip it
[Applause]
what are you she's like me
i was like yeah you what are you she's
like i
am a loofah
[Laughter]
are you a dirty officer
maybe
she's like good and i'm like you know i
realize with all the stuff going on with
cops around the country that we got to
be proactive right and building rapports
with citizens you know what i'm saying
so i'm like i got you sister i grabbed
the strobe lights i turned them all on i
grabbed my pa and i'm all
she's like oh my goodness i didn't know
we were gonna make money i got you
that's the scariest thing you've ever
seen
i sure hope he knows where the end of
the stage is
timber
we got a patron down in the front row
patriots
mexican down too michigan
so i'm into it right i got this side of
the street
this side of the street
what not paying attention
there comes my supervisor driving around
the corner
i know right
i didn't know what to do
so i tased the loofah
twice
that's a little too much clapping back
there sir he should have done it third
time third time
everything isn't cooler now some things
were more fun when i was little
halloween used to be more fun
halloween's sad now kids trick-or-treat
in the middle of the afternoon
they only go to the houses of people
that they already know oh that's spooky
when i was little we had to face fear
and earn our candy
my parents would drive me somewhere in
the middle of the night
drop me off alone
make me trick-or-treat my way back to
the house
i didn't know where i was and i couldn't
see out of my mask
i just say trick-or-treat
do you know which way i live
that always put me in the same homemade
costume an all-black costume with no
reflectors
i don't want to be a ninja again
tommy remember ninjas are quiet
and they walk in the middle of the
street
if you're lucky enough to make it home
what you have to do back then dump all
your candy out on the floor spread it
out if anything was unwrapped or
tampered with you had to eat that right
away
because it could go bad
most of stand-up comedy is exaggeration
i wish i was exaggerating this next
story
i had a kid come to my door
trick-or-treating last year at three in
the afternoon five-year-old boy dressed
as the devil
i opened the door ticker t
trick-or-treat is the middle of the day
why aren't you trick-or-treating after
dark he goes i'm scared of the dark
you're the devil
you're the prince of darkness
halloween's about fear you can't handle
fear you're not getting any candy get
into character and i closed the door
feeling pretty good about myself till a
minute later when the devil's mom came
to the door
she is way scarier than the devil
[Laughter]
my mom hates me
i have two sisters one's a doctor one's
a lawyer and i'm this
i'm doing dry bar comedy my mom hates me
my mom's favorite day of the year is
halloween because for one day a year her
son's a doctor
which is very mean
my mom said not dude every time i upset
her she makes me do weird stuff like a
punishment that i don't even see coming
until it happens
last year she made me take my cousin
trick-or-treating for halloween
i was like of course i will i don't care
i love halloween let's go i'll go pick
up my cousin 11 year old indian kid you
know what he's dressed like
a slurpee
us i wanted to knock the straw off his
head i'm like why
are you dressed like a slurpee you're
indian
people make fun of us about this why
would you decide to dress yourself up
like a slurpee
but i couldn't say any of that because i
was dressed like aladdin
i could say
nothing i was like just hop on the
carpet it's gonna be a long ride
it's the worst
hey halloween you guys like halloween
isn't a great holiday i like i think i
never liked it when i was growing up i
lived on a farm maybe out there grew up
on a farm
you live on a farm halloween stinks you
go trick-or-treating the next house is
eight miles away
you walk eight miles a man hands you an
apple here you go son
oh gee thank you mister we don't have
these things on our farm
what do you call them again
it's a weird holiday you have to go out
and you buy candy and give it to other
people's children you try that any other
time of year you're going to prison
and i ran out of can anybody ever run
out of candy on halloween
i granted well first of all i ate it
but it's not my fault they start selling
it in july
i buy it in july by october half of it
is gone
and then last year i ran out again seven
o'clock i was out of county nothing left
i turned off the lights and they're
still knocking on the door
i'm behind the couch hiding from them go
away
the light is off don't you know the
rules
they still kept coming you know i ended
up giving out
expired cans of stuff
[Music]
trick-or-treat
green beans
one little kid says i'm going to give
your house a bad report review on yelp
i like it
i guess you had to be there
man you guys had a good
oh halloween it's a fun holiday i wasn't
allowed to celebrate halloween when i
was a kid
my mom told me it was the devil's
holiday
have you guys heard that before yeah
yeah i wasn't allowed to celebrate ever
then i went to college grew up
did a little bit of research found out
it's not the devil's holiday
that's um columbus day
yeah
you guys went to school yeah
he was satan he's
[Laughter]
i don't think my mom let me celebrate
halloween because
she didn't want to spend the money on a
costume
every time i asked for something she was
like you think money grows on trees huh
we're poor i can't afford we can't
afford costumes and candy
and i'm like we
we're poor i'm six i don't
how did my decisions end up here huh how
did
you don't consult with me with the bills
okay
i'm not even old enough to work how are
we broke i don't understand
i don't even know my social security
number right
you're poor mom
my teacher told me i had potential she
says
she says i could be anything i want to
be you're poor mom you messed up i don't
know what happened
but don't shame me okay that's on you
mama
that's great i'm from minnesota so to me
utah seems like a multicultural paradise
with a tropical climate and
i got off the plane and i was like am i
in miami this is great
that's great to be at this is such a
beautiful venue too this place is
amazing
i feel a little underdressed
i'm not wearing any underwear right now
um
don't worry you're fine i'm front you're
saying it's a clean show don't worry
you're fine
i'm not wearing any underwear because my
wife and i are at the end of a laundry
cycle right now
and the first one of us to acknowledge
that they're out of clothes
that's right they're gonna have to do
that laundry
and it is not gonna be this guy
my wife thought she won the whole thing
last night i got out of the shower and i
dried myself off with like six or seven
washcloths
[Laughter]
and i went out into the living room and
there she was
laying on the couch eating a big bag of
cheetos
in her wedding dress
[Laughter]
looking pretty smug about it
i didn't say a word to her i just put on
an old halloween costume and went to bed
it did backfire on me at like two in the
morning i got up to go to the bathroom
and i walked by a mirror and freaked
myself out a little bit
like oh my gosh it's a saucy nurse
[Laughter]
she's not wearing any underwear
and she's got a secret
so i did mention that i did have a
batman themed wedding and that is a
hundred percent true it's uh one of the
coolest days of my my life i'm i'm so
happy my wife thought of it so as you
guys can imagine my favorite holiday is
halloween
i like a lot more now as a as an adult
because as a kid my family did not have
a lot of money so halloween was never a
priority to us and it hurt because i go
trick-or-treating with my friends and
you know my buddy steve was superman he
had the muscles and the cape and my
buddy justin was a gi joe he had the
camouflage face paint camouflage gear
the boots toy gun
you know and it hurt because i had to
make my own costume for several years
and the only thing i could do is i take
a big red rope and hold it over my head
just like this i'll go door-to-door
trick-or-treating and people be like
little boy where are you supposed to be
and i would tell them i'm a child living
below the poverty line
and i got twice as much candy as all the
other kids
i know i'm a pretty smart idiot
so when we came to america my dad didn't
understand halloween it just freaked him
out
the doorbell would ring he would hide
and be like martin
spiderman here to rob us
like dad they're kids they just want
candy he's like we don't have candy
give him our vcr and your brother
i'm like mom's gonna kill you he's like
you're right
keep the vcr
i uh was in a hotel recently
they had one of those memory foam
mattresses you know the ones you sink
into it it remembers your shape
very comfortable mattress i do not
recommend it if you already have
self-esteem issues about your body
[Music]
because the last thing you want to see
first thing in the morning
is that giant crater you left in the
memory foam
it's no way to start the day
it's not any better on skinny people i
wake up looks like a halloween
decoration was laying there
i'm like oh man i can see my rib cage
that's not healthy
i should start doing push-ups i did a
good job on the view so they kept
calling me back i eventually became a
writer for one of the co-hosts so i
would have to take serious stuff and
flip it
make it funny for them wasn't always
easy because they had passed the law in
simi valley california and they said if
you were a registered sex offender and
you wanted to decorate your house for
halloween you had to put a sign on your
door
saying you were registered
so the registered people
was all upset if we put this sign on our
door ain't no kids coming to our house
yeah that's the point
we already we already paid our dues we
already did our times it don't matter
some things that don't matter you mess
with kids you don't get to be around
kids no more
you robber
give it up
you rob a bank you don't get to be a
teller
now if i was to get arrested for not
paying my taxes
when i get out
i should not be allowed to ever be
around taxes again
[Applause]
i should be able to walk it to the
99-cent store and give them a dollar
no excuse me sir it's a dollar seven no
excuse me
i am a registered tax offender
i can't be around taxes no more
so can you just give me my penny please
yeah i know thank you yeah it is what it
is
you know what the second most popular
holiday is in the united states
halloween
so let's weigh it out shall we peace on
earth
goodwill towards men and
equally uplifting don't you think
and by the way have you ever noticed
that boo's the only scare word we know
that's all we got and it's not
inherently scary watch
so why do people that use it think they
did something creative boom gotcha okay
now it's the fact you were hiding in the
refrigerator that's what got me
could've said pretty much anything
monkey ran sure okay
i don't celebrate halloween i'll tell
you why because it's an inherently
flawed holiday here's how it's supposed
to work trick or treat i tricked you you
got to give me candy
problem is she didn't trick me you
always come on the same day
hence the bag of candy i had prepared
no tricks oh no treat
the only trick-or-treat would really
work is if you came like in may
three o'clock in the morning what is
going on drink a dream
you got me okay
wow all right uh here's a pickle okay